cabelas.ca 2018-12-25

# Cabela's Canada

AT CABELA'S CANADA WE RESPECT AND VALUE YOUR PRIVACY

 **Cabela’s Retail Canada Inc. Privacy Statement**

Last updated: June 14, 2016

This Privacy Statement sets out the manner in which Cabela’s Retail Canada Inc. (“Cabela’s Canada”) collects, uses, discloses and otherwise manages the personally identifiable information of its customers, including the privacy practices of our retail store, catalogue services, and website located at  **www.cabelas.ca**.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Statement, you should first contact us via Customer Service email at [ **privacyofficer@cabelas.ca**](mailto:privacyofficer@cabelas.ca) or by calling  **18002656245**. Or if you prefer to write us, please send it to:

**Cabela's Retail Canada Inc.    
Privacy Officer  
25 De Baets St.,   
Winnipeg, Manitoba Canada R2J 4G5**

**Cabela's Canada Privacy Statement will inform you about:**

  * What personally identifiable information is being collected and used?
  * With whom does Cabela’s Canada share your information?
  * How to access, update, or correct your personally identifiable information.
  * What information will be disclosed if required by law?
  * What are cookies and how does Cabela’s Canada use them?
  * What choices are available to you regarding the collection, use and disclosure of the information and how you can correct any inaccuracies in information?
  * What kind of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under the control of Cabela’s Canada?

**Privacy**

**_What personally identifiable information is being collected and used?_**

In general, you can visit the Cabela’s Canada website without telling us who you are or providing us with any personally identifiable information. However, in order for us to provide you with the products, services or other information that you have requested, you may be asked to provide us with personally identifiable information. For example, when you order a product, we may ask you to become a registered user of our website, during which you will be asked for your name, shipping and billing addresses, your email address, and your telephone number. Similarly, when you purchase products through our catalogue, we collect the name, address, email address and telephone number of the purchaser. We may also collect the name, address and telephone number of the person to whom the items are to be shipped (if different than the purchaser). Third-party shipping information shall only be used for the purpose of processing and fulfilling the order. The information we collect is used to process your order and provide you with the products and services you have requested. You do not have to provide us with any personally identifiable information when you purchase products at our retail store by cash.

If you use a credit or debit card to purchase a product online, instore, or through our catalogue, your payment card-related information and your signature will be collected for the purposes of processing your payment. If you pay for a purchase by money order, cheque or C.O.D, the name, address, email address and telephone number of the purchaser will be collected in order to identify you and contact you regarding your payment, if necessary.

If you request to receive our catalogues, emails, newsletters, or other marketing materials we may collect your name, address, telephone number and email address. If you wish to stop receiving any of these materials, you may contact us at  **1.800.265.6245** , send us an email at [ **privacyofficer@cabelas.ca**](mailto:privacyofficer@cabelas.ca), or write us at the postal address provided above. Email recipients can also opt-out from receiving future emails by using the opt-out link in each email.

If you request, we may make your postal mailing address information available to subsidiaries and affiliated companies that are part of the Cabela's family of companies, or to other direct mail companies who we believe may have products and services of interest to our customers, for the marketing purposes of those companies. If you wish to stop receiving any of these materials, you may contact us at  **18002656245** , send us an email at [ **privacyofficer@cabelas.ca**](mailto:privacyofficer@cabelas.ca), or write us at the postal address provided above.

If you contact our customer service representatives by telephone or email we may collect your name, address, telephone number and email address. We may store a record of your request/inquiry along with your name, address and other personal contact information you provide to assist you in the future and to improve our products and services.

If you provide us with your email address when you purchase a product or service, you may receive messages about your order status, issues regarding the operations of this website, and messages from affiliates of Cabela's Canada and other companies with operational relationships to Cabela's.

When purchasing on our website or through our catalogues we may request your telephone number or facsimile (fax) number; and, if you provide it, you may receive telephone or fax contact from us with information regarding your orders.

We may post customer testimonials on our website which may contain personally identifiable information such as the customer's name. We do obtain the customer's consent prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial.

When you order a gift card we collect information regarding the amount of the gift card and information you may provide about the recipient such as the name, address and telephone number of the party receiving the gift card as well as any message you provide on a gift card. This information is only used for the purpose of processing and fulfilling your gift card order.

When you enter a contest or participate in a promotion, we may collect your name, address, phone number, email address, and other information that you provide. We use this information to administer your participation in the contest or promotion. At the time you enter the contest or promotion, we may obtain your consent to send you future promotional communications from Cabela’s Canada or its marketing partners. If a contest or promotion is jointly sponsored by us and one or more sponsors, your personal information may be shared with such sponsors, as specified at the time of collection of your personal information. We do not control the use, disclosure or security of your personal information by other sponsors, and recommend you review their respective privacy notices or statements.

We may collect optional information such as your postal code or phone number and responses to questions about your purchasing preferences. We may use this information to help us carry the right assortment of products for your needs and to tailor the promotional material you receive.

The "Forward To A Friend" (or other similar implementation) function commonly associated with email messages will allow us to send an email to another recipient on your behalf. This requires that you submit your name and email address, as well as the name and email address of the recipient. The recipient will receive a single introductory email but must then opt-in to confirm their willingness to receive future emails. We do not use the names or email addresses submitted in these circumstances for any other purpose without the consent of you or the email recipient.

In addition, our Web servers track various technical details about your visit, such as your computer's IP address, page requests, browser type, operating system, referring page, and average time spent on the website, however that information does not typically contain any personally identifiable information about you. We use this information to monitor and improve our website.

In connection with a job application or related inquiry, we collect certain personal information you provide about yourself, such as that contained in a resumé or similar employment-related materials. We use this information to process and respond to your application or inquiry.

**_With whom does Cabela’s Canada share your information?_**

Except as otherwise set out in the Privacy Statement, we will not disclose, trade, rent, sell or otherwise transfer your personal information without your consent.

In order to operate the Cabela’s Canada website and in order to provide you with the products and services you have requested, we occasionally need to share information with our affiliates and other third parties who provide services on our behalf. We may transmit your personal information to service providers who assist us in processing orders, shipping products to you, processing your payment information, sending you catalogues, conducting surveys, on and offline sweepstakes, processing job applications, and sending you emails and newsletters. Your personal information may be stored and processed within Canada and the United States by our affiliates and other third-party service providers. Our service providers are required to implement measures to safeguard your personal information, use it only in compliance with applicable privacy laws, and are prohibited from using or disclosing your personal information for any purpose other than providing the services on our behalf or as otherwise legally required.

We may transfer any information we have about you as an asset in connection with a merger or sale (including transfers made part of insolvency or bankruptcy proceedings) involving all or part of Cabela’s Canada or as part of a corporate reorganization or stock sale or other change in corporate control.

**_How to access, update, or correct my personally identifiable information._**

If you are a registered user of our website, you can manage many aspects of your registration information online. For security reasons, however, some parts of your personal information may not be changed online and may require you to call or write to us in order to verify your identity before such changes can be made. The online registration area will also permit you to exercise control over the use of your email address, allowing you to opt-out of future email messages from Cabela’s Canada. If you prefer to manage your personal information via other means, or if you would like to access, update, or correct any of your personal information we have in our possession, you may contact us at  **18002656245** , send us an email at [ **privacyofficer@cabelas.ca**](mailto:privacyofficer@cabelas.ca), or write us at the postal address provided above.

**_What information will be disclosed if required by law?_**

If required by law, we may provide any and all information we have about you to law enforcement or other government agencies, pursuant to a subpoena, warrant, or other order by a court of competent jurisdiction. Cabela’s Canada and our service providers must provide your personal information in response to a search warrant or other legally valid inquiry or order, or to an investigative body in the case of a breach of an agreement or contravention of law, or as otherwise required by law. We may also disclose personal information to assist us in collecting a debt owed by you, or otherwise where necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

**_What are cookies and how does Cabela’s Canada use them?_**

A cookie is a block of text placed in a file on the user's hard drive by a website you've visited. These types of cookies cannot identify an individual user specifically, such as by name or address, unless the cookie data is attached to personally identifiable information such as online registration. Cabela's Canada uses cookies to observe our site visitor's navigation throughout the site. This helps us identify ways to improve the shopping experience.

Cabela's Canada also uses a session cookie, which is a piece of identification between your browser and our server, which helps to do things like keep track of the items in a user's shopping cart, and other information. The shopping cart cookie is saved for a designated period of time in case the users' session expires or they return to complete a purchase within that time frame. You may set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie. However, should you decide not to accept cookies from the Cabela’s Canada website, you may limit the functionality we can provide when you visit our website.

This website also uses the following:

**Google Analytics:** This cookie allows us to see information on user website activities including, but not limited to page views, source and time spent on website.This information is depersonalized and is displayed as numbers, meaning that it cannot be tracked back to individuals. You may optout of our use of Google Analytics by visiting the [Google Analytics opt-out page](https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=https-3A__tools.google.com_dlpage_gaoptout&d=CwMFAw&c=_mDkRWzOLjoVDgT8Mi46Yw&r=m-JXY0dhV-lQGVdvUolvCHS98-dzsnxvTqMxUATAv-Y&m=xVQy6X9NrejkDy3E0Hp_xJIKNR843d8yY5C22GrhngA&s=eFAEf8cG7P19Nx-orMExIZDgxR1YvQAJmIYgEfYcpMM&e=).

**Google AdWords:** We use Google AdWords Remarketing to advertise Cabela’s Canada across the Internet and to advertise on third party websites (including Google) to previous visitors to our site. AdWords remarketing will display ads to you based on what parts of the Cabela’s Canada website you have viewed by placing a cookie on your web browser. It could mean that we advertise to previous visitors who haven’t completed a task on our site or this could be in the form of an advertisement on the Google search results page, or a site in the Google Display Network. This cookie does not in any way identify you or give access to your computer or mobile device. The cookie is only used to indicate to other websites that you have visited a particular page on our website, so that they may show you ads relating to that page. If you do not wish to participate in our Google AdWords Remarketing, you can opt out by visiting [Google's Ads Preferences Manager](https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=https-3A__www.google.com_settings_ads_onweb_-3Fsig-3DACi0TCh1yimtGw-5FMCXmyADlHvvNP9ru5SKV9iAKbteqQbUDtboQl0SdUSbwEmoNTXTgnRO-2DcibkW-2DSaqoP-5FhqySYAEFc81F3x-5FCPdSfJh9l-5FRsKo6erVcaAnk4XgPtkkyHbV1Pv9yO1rb7AzNUD5rsTct1zzgNfoKIMUxeDT-5F4FkzCX6sP9tVEyhCzqG6ROQv5tCMf7yyMFhq2MtTRDLTch9bUH9Q9dB0jgIfyeRddAr5tNKR0-2DC4y20NKYzNXgSDMWONWdq4fSi-26amp-3Bhl-3Den&d=CwMFAw&c=_mDkRWzOLjoVDgT8Mi46Yw&r=m-JXY0dhV-lQGVdvUolvCHS98-dzsnxvTqMxUATAv-Y&m=xVQy6X9NrejkDy3E0Hp_xJIKNR843d8yY5C22GrhngA&s=hCteGHMIO4jnfkQbmcKtGxWUpUUX2atGlpod_yE0Ycc&e=).”

**_What choices are available to you regarding the collection, use and disclosure of the information?_**

If you do not want to receive mail from us in the future, please let us know by calling  **18002656245** , send an email to [ **privacyofficer@cabelas.ca**](mailto:privacyofficer@cabelas.ca), or write to us at the above postal address and telling us that you do not want to receive mail from our company.

With your consent you may also receive emails from us containing information about new products and services or upcoming events. You may modify your email preferences by calling  **1.800.265.6245**  or, if you have established a profile at www.cabelas.ca, you may change your email preferences in the " **My Profile** " section by clicking there. If you receive email from Cabela’s Canada and do not wish to you may unsubscribe using the the opt-out link provided within our emails.

On occasion, we may make our postal mailing address lists available to subsidiaries and affiliated companies that are part of the Cabela's family of companies, or to other direct mail companies who we believe may have products and services of interest to our customers, for the marketing purposes of those companies. We will only share your personal information with those companies for such purposes if we have received your prior consent. If we obtained your consent and you no longer wish to receive postal mailings from Cabela's Canada, its affiliated companies, or third-party organizations, please let us know by calling, sending an email to info@cabelas.ca, or writing to us at the above postal address. Please provide us with your exact name, postal address and the list you wish to be removed from, so that we can be sure your information is removed from future mailings.

**Security**

**_What kind of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under the control of Cabela’s Canada?_**

Cabela's Canada values your business and is committed to doing everything possible to make our online ordering process secure. We have implemented measures in an effort to maintain the security of the personally identifiable information in our custody and control, including providing access to personally identifiable information to only those employees and authorized service providers who require such information for the purposes described in this Privacy Statement. We maintain reasonable administrative, technical and physical safeguards in an effort to protect against unauthorized access, use, modification and disclosure of personal information in our custody and control. Unfortunately, no collection or transmission of information over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure, and therefore, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any such information.

Due to various legal and record-keeping requirements, we may be required to maintain records about your purchases or other activities on the Cabela’s Canada website. Your personal information will be retained for as long as it remains necessary for the purpose stated in this Privacy Statement or as otherwise required or permitted by law.

**Secure Ordering Process**

Any credit card information you enter on our site is encrypted by industry-standard protocol, SSL (Secure Sockets Layer). The Cabela's Canada website uses SSL to communicate with secure browsers like Netscape, Mozilla, Firefox and Internet Explorer.

If you are still unsure about giving your credit card over the Internet, please feel free to phone, fax or mail your order to us. For telephone ordering or assistance, please call  **18002656245**. Our fax number for orders is  **12047868964**. Or, send your order to:

**Cabela's Retail Canada Inc.  
Attn: Order Desk   
 **25 De Baets St.,    
Winnipeg, Manitoba **** ** **Canada R2J 4G5****

If you have any further questions regarding your online security, please contact us at  **18002656245**  or email [ **Customer Service**](mailto:info@cabelas.ca).

**Third-party Links**

Our website may contain links to other sites that we do not own or operate. Also, links to our website may be featured on other websites on which we advertise. Except as provided herein, we will not provide any of your personal information to these third parties without your prior consent. We provide links to third party websites as a convenience to the user. These linked websites have separate and independent privacy policies, which we recommend you read carefully. We may not have any control over such websites, and therefore we have no responsibility or liability for the manner in which the organizations that operate such linked websites may collect, use or disclose and otherwise treat your personal information

**Children**

If you are under the legal age of majority within your jurisdiction, you are welcome to browse our website. However, you are not permitted to use any of the features of our site that require the collection of any personally identifiable information. If we determine that we have erroneously collected information from an individual who is not a legal adult, we will immediately undertake to delete that data from our records.

**Changes in this Privacy Statement**

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this statement, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page. We will use and disclose your personal information in accordance with the Privacy Statement in place at the time of collection of such information, or as you otherwise consent as permitted by law.
